Finding Aid for Athletic Department (University of Michigan) records, 1860-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Athletic Director's Office
  - Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics
    - Correspondence
      - 1981-1982 (Box 92)
      - 1983-1985 (Box 92)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 92)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 92)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 92)
      - 1992 (Box 92)
      - 1993 (Box 92)
    - Topical Files
      - Alternate Faculty Representative to Big Ten 1981 (Box 92)
      - Anton, Thomas (Box 92)
      - "Johnson Report," 1987-1988 (Box 92)
        (Report of a committee headed by Prof. Harold Johnson on administration of athletics)
      - "Nordby Report," 1985 (Box 92)
        (concerning integration of women's athletics into Big Ten programs)
      - Retreats 1990-1991 (Box 92)
      - "Questions and Answers" 1971 (Box 92)
  - William Martin Files
    - Correspondence
      - 2004, 5 folders (Box 92)
      - 2005, 4 folders (Box 92)
      - 2006, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - 2007, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - 2008, 4 folders (Box 92)
      - 2009, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - 2009-2010 (Box 225)
      - Alumni Clubs 2003-2006 (Box 225)
      - Big Ten 2003-2007 (Box 225)
      - CORR Condolences 2005-2007 (Box 225)
      - Football 2004 (Box 225)
      - Guest Services 2004-2009 (Box 225)
      - Sent to U-M Regents 2004, 2009 (Box 225)
    - Banners 1995-2000 (Box 225)
    - Big Ten Core Values Visit December 13, 2004 (Box 225)
    - Football and Basketball Seat Change Requests 2000-2006 (Box 225)
    - Gary's Banners 2002 (Box 225)
    - Eddie Martin Indictment 2002 (Box 225)
    - No Fly Zone 2001-2003 (Box 225)
    - Sports Venue Security 2001 (Box 225)
    - United States Olympic Foundation 2007 (Box 225)
    - USA Boxing 2006 (Box 225)
- Development Office
  The Development Office sub-group consists primarily of brochures and reports on endowment, Fund-raising, promotional and award programs; material relating to booster clubs of various sports; and reports, programs and directories of the Victors Club, Maize and Blue Club, and Kids Go Blue Club.
  - Topical File
    - Abbott, Jim (Box 57)
    - Academic Achievement Awards Banquet 1991-2000 (Box 57)
    - Advertising and Corporate Promotions 1999 (Box 57)
    - Annual Report and Honor Roll 1994/95, 1999/00-2001/03 (Box 57)
    - Athletic Endowment Program, 1993- (Box 57)
    - Athletic Scholarship Fund, (circa 1969-1980 (Box 57)
    - Booster Clubs and Support Groups
      - Booster Club Brochures, (Blue Aces, Dekers, Swish Club, etc.) 1994- (Box 57)
      - University of Michigan Club of Ann Arbor (Basketball Bust) (Box 57)
      - University of Michigan Club of Chicago (Box 57)
      - University of Michigan Club of Detroit
        - Football Bust 1948-1950, 1958-1961, 1964-1965, 1967, 1969-1971, 1973, 1975-1980, 1983-1985, 1988-1989, 1994 (Box 57)
      - Varsity M Club 1950-1951, 1957 (Box 57)
      - Victors Club & Maize and Blue Club
        - Annual Report and Directory 1969-1972, 1977, 1981-1984, 1987, 1993 (Box 57)
        - Brochures (Box 57)
        - "Year In Review," 1994/95 (Box 57)
        - Annual Report DVD 2004/05 2006/072007/08 (Box 223)
        - Fall Kickoff Event 2001-2003 (Box 57)
          (brochures, contact sheets)
        - Spring event (Box 57)
        - Director's Circle 2007 (Box 57)
        - Wolverine Welcome 2008 (Box 57)
      - Campaign For Michigan 1993 (Box 57)
      - Events
        - Basketball reception 2007 (Box 57)
        - 1989 Team Reunion, 2009 (Box 57)
        - Bo Schembechler Reception, April 30 2005 (Box 57)
        - Bo's Barbecue, 200 (Box 57)
        - Captains and Coaches 2006 (Box 57)
        - Champions Golf Tournament 2006 (Box 57)
        - Director's Circle Tailgate 2007 (Box 57)
        - Early Women in Athletics Ceremony, September 7 2008 (Box 57)
        - Endowed Scholarship Donor Recognition 2002-2003, 2 folders (Box 57)
        - First Letter Reception 2007/08 (Box 57)
        - Wolverine Welcome September 3, 2008 (Box 57)
      - Hall of Honor (Box 260)
        - Programs 1978-1986, 1987-1989, 1992, 1994, 1996, 2008-2010 (Box 260)
        - Photos 2007-2009 (Box 260)
      - Holiday Cards (Box 260)
      - Kids Go Blue Club
        - Newsletter
          - 1992/93 (Box 260)
          - 1993/94 (Box 260)
          - 1994/95 (Box 260)
        - Promotional Material (Box 260)
    - Merchandise Catalogs (Box 260)
    - Michigan Stadium Brick
      - Digital images 2009 (Box 223)
    - Miscellaneous Promotions (Box 261)
    - Mock Rock, programs 2000, 2002, 2006 (Box 261)
    - Reunions
      - 1989 Basketball National Champions (Box 261)
      - Football 130 Year All-Time Reunion (Box 261)
      - Tennis November 16-17, 2007 (Box 261)
    - Summer Camps (Box 261)
    - Sports Management Institute 2006 (Box 261)
    - Wolverine Welcome 2008 (Box 261)
    - Ticket Sales and Promotion
      - Basketball (Box 261)
      - Football 1962-1995 (Box 261)
      - Gymnastics (Box 261)
      - Hockey (Box 261)
      - Track (Box 261)
      - Women's Sports (Box 261)
    - Yost Honor Award Programs 1967-1968 (Box 261)
  - Buildings and Facilities (Fund raising brochures and dedication programs, photos)
    - Canham Natatorium (Box 60)
    - Crisler Arena (University Events Building) (Box 60)
    - Donald Shepherd Building, Women's Gymnastics August, 31 2002 (Box 60)
    - Football Indoor Practice Building 2008 (Box 60)
    - Golf Course (Box 60)
    - J. Ira and Nicki Harris Football Locker Room November 21, 2003 (Box 60)
    - Junge Family Champions Center and Mortenson Family Plaza (Box 60)
    - Michigan Stadium Expansion
      - Brochure and renderings (Box 60)
      - Construction "Topping Off" Ceremony Photos August 18, 2008, CD and contact prints (Box 60)
    - Schembechler Hall (Box 60)
    - Stephen M. Ross Academic Center, May, 18 2004
      - Brochures and Contact sheets (Box 60)
    - Tennis Complex (Box 60)
    - Track and Tennis Building (Box 60)
    - Wilpon Baseball and Softball Complex 2008 (Box 60)
    - Wrestling Center
      - Brochures (Box 60)
      - Dedication Ceremony photos, CD and contact sheets (Box 60)
    - Yost Arena (Box 60)
- Business Office
  The Business Office sub-group includes three series of financial records: account books 1904-1941/1942; Audit Reports, 1922-1957/58; and Miscellaneous Accounts, 1925/26-1942/43.
  - Account Books
    - 1904-1910, 1 volumes (Box 58)
    - 1924/25 (Box 58)
    - 1925/26 (Box 58)
    - 1926/27 (Box 58)
    - 1927/28 (Box 58)
    - 1929/30 (Box 58)
    - 1930/31 (Box 58)
    - 1931/32 (Box 58)
    - 1932/33 (Box 58)
    - 1933/34 (Box 58)
    - 1934/35 (Box 58)
    - 1935/36 (Box 58)
    - 1936/37 (Box 58)
    - 1937/38 (Box 58)
    - 1940/41 (Box 58)
    - 1941/42 (Box 58)
  - Audit Reports
    - 1922 (Box 58)
    - 1928 (Box 58)
    - 1945/46-1947/48 (Box 58)
      (copy from Regents' Exhibit)
    - 1950/51-1951/52, 1953/54 (Box 58)
      (copy from Regents' Exhibits)
    - 1955/56-1957/58 (Box 58)
    - 1967/68-1969/70, 1971/72-1977/78 (Box 58)
    - 1978/79-1983/84, 1985/86-1986/87, 1988/89-1989/90 (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts
    - Account Book, ca 1922-1943, 1 volumes (Box 66A)
      (includes listing of expenses for construction of Yost Field House, Palmer Field, Michigan Stadium, Intramural Sports Building, and the Coliseum, as well some information on scheduling and ticket sales 1925/26-1942/43)
    - Football Game Program Revenues 1971-1989 (Box 66A)
- Ticket Office
  The Ticket Office subgroup consists of game reports, 1927-1968, listing ticket sales and revenues for each sport.
  - Game Reports
    - 1922-1924 (Box 83)
      (includes expense report on Yost Field House construction)
    - 1927/28-1939/40 (Box 83)
    - 1940/41-1944/45 (Box 83)
    - 1945/46-1947/48 (Box 83)
    - 1948/49-1952/53 (Box 83)
    - 1953/54-1956/57 (Box 83)
    - 1957/58-1960/61 (Box 83)
    - 1961/62 (Box 83)
    - 1964/65 (Box 83)
    - 1965/66 (Box 83)
    - 1966/67 (Box 83)
    - 1967/68 (Box 83)
- Compliance Office
  - NCAA Certification 1997
    - Committees
      - Steering Committee 1994-1996 (Box 104)
      - Liaison Department 1995 (Box 104)
      - Fiscal Integrity (Box 104)
      - NCAA Equity Subcommittee 1995-1996 (Box 104)
      - Governance and Rules Subcommittee 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - Academic Integrity Subcommittee 1995-1996, 5 folders (Box 104)
    - Topical Files
      - Procedural Information (Box 104)
      - Plan for Certification Review 1994 (Box 104)
      - Institutional Control 1996 (Box 104)
      - Task Force List and General Correspondence 1995 (Box 104)
      - Audit Reports-Ernst and Young 1993-1996 (Box 104)
      - University of Michigan Audits 1996 (Box 104)
      - Title IX Reviews Audit March 28, 1995 (Box 104)
        (by Miller, Canfield, Paddock and Stone)
      - Attorney's Preliminary Compliance Assessment and Recommendations April 8, 1996 (Box 104)
      - First Self-Study Questions (Box 104)
      - Self-Study Instrument 1996 (Box 104)
        (Includes Jeff Long memo and copies of Regents' Decisions concerning Athletic Department, 1992-1995)
      - Public Commentary 1996 (Box 104)
      - Media Articles 1995-1996 (Box 104)
      - NCAA visit information 1997 (Box 104)
    - Manuals and Policy Documents
      - Athletic Equipment Policy 1996/97 (Box 104)
      - Student Athlete Handbook 1995/96-1996/97 (Box 104)
      - Student Support Operations Manual 1996/97 (Box 104)
      - Policies for Student Athletes 1994-1996 (Box 104)
      - Compliance Program Operations Manual (Box 104)
      - Coaches Compliance Manual 1996/97 (Box 104)
      - Development and External Relations Manual (Box 104)
      - Business Operations Manual 1995 (Box 104)
      - Athletic Medicine Policy and Procedures Manual 1996/97
Related Material
The Bentley Historical Library hold numerous collections of personal papers and University of Michigan record groups which contain material relating to Michigan Athletics. These include papers of former coaches and athletic administrators; records of various university administrative offices which dealt with athletic matters; personal papers of U of M students which frequently include scrapbooks photographs and memorabilia; and collections of several photo studios. The library has a complete set of The Michiganensian, the school yearbook and it predecessors and an extensive collection of publications about University of Michigan athletics. Consult MIRLYN, the university's on-line catalog for a comprehensive listing. Among the more significant manuscript collections and record groups are:
Athletic Managers Club records, 1922-1969.
Bennie Gaylord Oosterbaan papers, 1921-1981.
Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics (University of Michigan) records, 1879 and 1891-1988.
Charles Baird papers, 1892-1933.
Clifford Keen papers, 1925-1985.
Dept. of Physical Education for Women (University of Michigan) records, 1878-1972.
Don Canham papers, 1968-1988.
Eunice L. Burns papers, 1960-1990.
Fielding Harris Yost papers, ca. 1900-1971.
H. O. Crisler papers, 1922-1978.
Harry G. Kipke papers, 1917-1938.
Ivory Photo photograph collection.
James Orin Murfin papers, 1896-1940.
John R. Behee sound recordings.
Joyce Lindeman papers, 1955-1984.
Marie D. Hartwig papers, 1927-1988.
Michigan Daily photograph series. (1963-1995)
News and Information Services (University of Michigan) photograph series.
Ralph Stone papers, 1882-1956.
Rentschler's Studio photograph collection.
University of Michigan photographs vertical file.
Walter DeWitt Graham scrapbooks, 1900-1908.
Wilfred Byron Shaw visual materials series.
Women's Athletic Association (University of Michigan) records, 1905-1962.
Women's Athletics (University of Michigan) records, 1972-[ongoing].